<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/fenilsuchak/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/fenilsuchak/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-03T12:33:23+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/fenilsuchak/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Fenil Suchak</title><subtitle>Hi my name is</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Work as a reflection of Self</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/fenilsuchak/non-tech/2020/04/11/first-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Work as a reflection of Self" /><published>2020-04-11T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-04-11T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/fenilsuchak/non-tech/2020/04/11/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/fenilsuchak/non-tech/2020/04/11/first-post/">&lt;p&gt; It's been a year since I had first planned to setup this blog page, and yet after a year I come up with this simplistic design. Dark blue background and silver font and a super static website, fuck there's not even a drop down anywhere. Probably it's me, I like retro simple stuff, raw stuff. It's not that I took long to create this blog, took me 2-3 days. I knew I wanted to setup a blog but I didn't know what to write, why to write. &lt;br&gt; &quot;Oh dude, do it for the resume.&quot; &lt;br&gt; &quot;Cool, makes sense&quot;. &lt;br&gt; But fuck no, I wasn't going to do that. I wanted to write something that reflects my style, my ideas, share my understanding to help others, not because I wanted to do it to achieve something else. I write because I want to, can't function well without putting it out there. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; So it's been four years of college and I'm convinced that I've been completely tranformed into a non-doer. I don't take action unless I'm told to or have a deadline. Procastination has become the universal truth, and for some reason sounds cool these days. I only function at (d - e) before the deadline. This assignments and regular lab culture has made me sick, there have been very few assignments which actually made me want to do it, because at the end I built something and yeah building is fun and it's real. If you tell me to look up stuff and write your understanding of it, fuck no I'm not going to do it, I'll borrow someones work but not do it. I hate fuckin learning that way, it's toxic to me, it makes me a mere consumer and I hate that thought. It does not reflect me, and the evaluator just assigns an integer and shoves it away. What the fuck is the point? How can that work make you feel any better, it's miserable. Do you guys agree? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, it is very well suited for some people who value those integers and are ever in that race ruthlessly to get those integers and obviously even the market does value them immensely, but I just can't make pretend that it's ok for me, I tried, a lot. It puts you in a very consumer mindset and that things in life will be asked and you just need to fill in. It's hard to switch this mindset when no one asks you to do it, when there's no deadlines, this model will drastically fail there. I know, I know, this model is made so that we are deliverable to the corporates or higher education. But I'm done. College ended on 29th April and there's just a final exam left. I'm done with this education after that, no more. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I at times feel that programming itself is pretty soul less, it doesn't have your reflection to it. It's just between if it works or not, if it has the highest score on test set or not. Pretty binary. I understand that building systems at scale, writing managabale software is a true art. But what I mean to say is when you are in an organization and build something, something that's really helpful, scalable and no doubt is a masterpiece of a work, then it gets injected into the system as a small lego block and is it is gone, individuality is lost. And after that if you leave the origanization, it might be replaced in the future without me ever knowing or ever contributing to it again. Get what I'm saying?, In this aspect I think research makes more sense and fits my values, but I seem terrible at it, just out of my league, many of my college friends are excellent at research and probably will agree with what I have to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it only makes sense to put great software/code out on github so it has a life of it's own and it being there and improved by brains all over the world, and I see it grow as a child. 
Just like the heroes did, like how Linux and Git reflect Linus Torvalds' ideas. Keras reflects Sir François Chollet and his philosophy. Arch Linux reflects Felix Yan's insane work ethic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yeah this is it for this piece, I have got a six month internship at a startup ahead of me to keep me busy till December, which hopefully will help me remove what I call the &lt;strong&gt;&quot;Student's Block&quot;&lt;/strong&gt; from my mind and body.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fenil Suchak</name></author><category term="non-tech" /><summary type="html">It's been a year since I had first planned to setup this blog page, and yet after a year I come up with this simplistic design. Dark blue background and silver font and a super static website, fuck there's not even a drop down anywhere. Probably it's me, I like retro simple stuff, raw stuff. It's not that I took long to create this blog, took me 2-3 days. I knew I wanted to setup a blog but I didn't know what to write, why to write. &quot;Oh dude, do it for the resume.&quot; &quot;Cool, makes sense&quot;. But fuck no, I wasn't going to do that. I wanted to write something that reflects my style, my ideas, share my understanding to help others, not because I wanted to do it to achieve something else. I write because I want to, can't function well without putting it out there.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">manga</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/fenilsuchak/non-tech/2020/04/08/second-post/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="manga" /><published>2020-04-08T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-04-08T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/fenilsuchak/non-tech/2020/04/08/second-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/fenilsuchak/non-tech/2020/04/08/second-post/">&lt;p&gt;   break &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src= &quot;/fenilsuchak/assets/img/blog/china.jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;   Back When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky mark Back When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky mark Back When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky mark Back When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky mark Back When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky mark Back When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky mark Back When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky mark Back When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky mark Back When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky mark Back When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky mark Back When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky mark Back When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky mark Back When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky mark Back When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky mark Back When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky mark Back When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky mark Back When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky mark Back When Mark Wahlberg was marky markBack When Mark Wahlberg was marky mark Back When Mark Wahlberg was marky mark&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fenil Suchak</name></author><category term="non-tech" /><summary type="html">inw</summary></entry></feed>