<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://192.168.101.42:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://192.168.101.42:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-10T18:12:01+05:30</updated><id>http://192.168.101.42:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Fenil Suchak</title><subtitle>Hi my name is</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Student’s Block</title><link href="http://192.168.101.42:4000/sugarcoated/students-block.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Student's Block" /><published>2020-05-06T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-06T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://192.168.101.42:4000/sugarcoated/students-block</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://192.168.101.42:4000/sugarcoated/students-block.html">&lt;quote&gt; &quot;It's not aimed at anyone it's just escaping on the run&quot; &lt;br&gt; &lt;auth&gt;- Bob Dylan, Mr. Tambourine Man &lt;/auth&gt;&lt;/quote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time not long ago (in 2016), I thought that I was onto something but It's been four years of college and I'm convinced that I've been completely transformed into a non-doer. I don't take action unless I'm told to or have a deadline. Procrastination has become the universal truth, and for some reason sounds cool these days. I only function at d - ε before the deadline. This assignments and regular lab culture have made me sick, there have been very few assignments which made me want to do it because at the end I built something and yeah building is fun and it's real. If you tell me to look up stuff and write your understanding of it, fuck no I'm not going to do it, I'll borrow someone's work but not do it. I hate fuckin learning that way, it's toxic to me, it makes me a mere consumer and I hate that thought. It does not reflect me, and the evaluator just assigns an integer and shoves it away. What the fuck is the point? How can that work make you feel any better, it's miserable. Do you guys agree?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sure, those integers have a long term monetary value and even the market does value them immensely, but I just can't make pretend that it's ok for me, I tried, a lot. It puts me in a very consumption mindset and that things in life will be asked explicitly and I just need to fill in time. It's hard to switch this mindset when no one asks you to do it when there are no deadlines, this model will straight fail there. I know, I know, this model is made so that we are deliverable to the corporates and higher education. But I'm done, college ended on 29th April and there's just a final exam left. I'm done with education after that, no more. I can't live this lifestyle of just learning and not producing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pessimism has been inevitable in college. I don't remember the last time I took any risk. The herd mentality has been so strong that I never bothered to look beyond what was required. I started with big dreams that I would have built something by the end of my 4th year (a personal OS was the idea) that would be recognized by peeps and would be hired based on that thing. But I couldn't, I didn't even try hard. I felt like it wasn't possible or worth it. Look at me now, doing interviewbit and gfg and preparing for placements. But over the last few months I've been thinking, is this all there is? Then why even put up a fight?. I still have that fire inside me and I've decided to start on my own by my 25th birthday. This target to chase would push me to see technology from all directions which until now I have been looking just through a consumers view and also to try out various ideas that I had documented but shoved away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So yeah this is it for this piece, I have got a six-month internship at a startup ahead of me to keep me busy till December, which hopefully will help me remove this &lt;strong&gt;Student's Block&lt;/strong&gt; from my mind and body.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Fenil Suchak</name></author><category term="non-tech" /><summary type="html">&quot;It's not aimed at anyone it's just escaping on the run&quot; - Bob Dylan, Mr. Tambourine Man Once upon a time not long ago (in 2016), I thought that I was onto something but It's been four years of college and I'm convinced that I've been completely transformed into a non-doer. I don't take action unless I'm told to or have a deadline. Procrastination has become the universal truth, and for some reason sounds cool these days. I only function at d - ε before the deadline. This assignments and regular lab culture have made me sick, there have been very few assignments which made me want to do it because at the end I built something and yeah building is fun and it's real. If you tell me to look up stuff and write your understanding of it, fuck no I'm not going to do it, I'll borrow someone's work but not do it. I hate fuckin learning that way, it's toxic to me, it makes me a mere consumer and I hate that thought. It does not reflect me, and the evaluator just assigns an integer and shoves it away. What the fuck is the point? How can that work make you feel any better, it's miserable. Do you guys agree? Sure, those integers have a long term monetary value and even the market does value them immensely, but I just can't make pretend that it's ok for me, I tried, a lot. It puts me in a very consumption mindset and that things in life will be asked explicitly and I just need to fill in time. It's hard to switch this mindset when no one asks you to do it when there are no deadlines, this model will straight fail there. I know, I know, this model is made so that we are deliverable to the corporates and higher education. But I'm done, college ended on 29th April and there's just a final exam left. I'm done with education after that, no more. I can't live this lifestyle of just learning and not producing. Pessimism has been inevitable in college. I don't remember the last time I took any risk. The herd mentality has been so strong that I never bothered to look beyond what was required. I started with big dreams that I would have built something by the end of my 4th year (a personal OS was the idea) that would be recognized by peeps and would be hired based on that thing. But I couldn't, I didn't even try hard. I felt like it wasn't possible or worth it. Look at me now, doing interviewbit and gfg and preparing for placements. But over the last few months I've been thinking, is this all there is? Then why even put up a fight?. I still have that fire inside me and I've decided to start on my own by my 25th birthday. This target to chase would push me to see technology from all directions which until now I have been looking just through a consumers view and also to try out various ideas that I had documented but shoved away. So yeah this is it for this piece, I have got a six-month internship at a startup ahead of me to keep me busy till December, which hopefully will help me remove this Student's Block from my mind and body.</summary></entry></feed>